adblockultimate.net 2019-03-30

# AdBlocker Ultimate - AND ALL ANNOYING ADS ARE OUT!

  *   * #### Privacy Policy AdBlocker Ultimate

##### General Note 

AdBlocker Ultimate is an add-on created to serve the user the best way possible. We do not collect any excess data. The only data we collect is used for the optimal functionality of our product. We take the privacy of your personal data very seriously and we make sure that we protect it the best way possible. The data is only used for purposes of our product and is never disclosed to third parties for any reason. Further you will read in detail the type of data we collect, how we process it if we do so, and how it is used. 

  * ## **Website Privacy Policy**

#### Data collected when using our website adblockultimate.net 

##### Cookies 

When browsing our website, we create a small data file on your hard drive called “cookies”. The browser stores the message in a text file and is sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from this server. The main purpose of the cookies is to identify the user and when possible to show them a customized web page that is appropriate for them to see. By continuing to use our website you agree to the use of cookies. The data recorder and received from the cookies is processed by different analytics tools. Some of them are used to determine your geographic location. Others are used to determine the type of device you are using to view our website (desktop computer, tablet, phone, etc.). Cookies usually expire within 30-60 days. Cookies only collect general behavioural information, they do not collect personally identifiable information for the user. You can always disable cookies in your web browser settings. 

  *   * ##### Google Analytics 

On adblockultimate.net we use Google Analytics to analyse the data from the website. In order for the analytics system to function it requires the collection of cookies. We use the data to (i) track and study the website’s usage and (ii) prepare reports on the website activity to fully understand users’ needs. 

  * ##### Further requests 

AdBlocker Ultimate may make further requests to the (adblockultimate.net) website as required. These requests are subject to the usual (adblockultimate.net) privacy policy.

  * ##### Contact Forms 

In our contact forms we require your e-mail address in order to be able to reply to your request. Your e-mail address is stored in our system. It is not used for anything other than just replying to your request. We do not use that e-mail for e-mail marketing or any other reason. Your e-mail is not disclosed to third parties.

  * ##### Third-party content and sites 

There might be times when you will find links to third-party websites on adblockultimate.net. Once you click on any of the links and continue using third-party websites you automatically agree to their privacy policy. 

  * ## **Extension Privacy Policy**

This part of the Privacy Policy refers to the extension AdBlocker Ultimate.

##### Update checks 

Browsers usually check for updates of the extensions you have installed and updates them. This is true for AdBlocker Ultimate too. General information is sent when this check runs (browser version, extension version, OS, IP address). The updates for AdBlocker Ultimate for Firefox are managed by the addons.mozilla.org website and are subject to Firefox Privacy Policy. The updates for AdBlocker Ultimate for Chrome are managed by the Google Web Store website and are subject to the Google Privacy Policy. The updates to AdBlocker Ultimate for Opera are managed by the Opera Add-ons website and are subject to the Opera Privacy Policy.

  * ##### Filter updates 

If you add filter subscriptions to your AdBlocker Ultimate installation, the subscription will be required to regularly get updates. Every update results in the hosting website receiving your IP address as well as some general information like your AdBlocker Ultimate version, browser and browser version. This data is subject to the privacy policy of the website in question.

Furthermore, if a subscription download fails on several consecutive occasions, the updated address of the filter list is requested from the (adblockultimate.net) domain. The data transmitted includes the AdBlocker Ultimate version, subscription address and any information about the error encountered. This data is used to identify issues that have not been reported by subscription maintainers and is subject to the usual AdblockUltimate.net privacy policy.

  * ##### Data storage 

AdBlocker Ultimate stores some data in your browser profile on your computer. AdBlocker Ultimate never transmits this data to any servers. Most of the data (your preferences, filter subscriptions and custom filters) is harmless privacy-wise. However, filter hit statistics and recent issue reports could be used to renovate your browsing history. AdBlocker Ultimate treats this information identically to how history data is treated by the browser: this data isn't stored if you are using Private Browsing mode and is removed if you choose to clear your browsing history.

  * ##### Donating 

When donating money for the development of the extension, we receive your e-mail. We keep this e-mail list in our system. We do not resell it or give it to third parties. This email list is only used to reach out with special offers connected to the AdBlocker Ultimate family of products.

  * ##### AdBlocker Ultimate Browser for iOS and Android 

When using AdBlocker Ultimate Browser some personal data is collected by itself or by third parties: Cookies, Usage Data, device identifiers for advertising, email address and various other types of data that is non sensitive. Personal data may be freely provided by the user, or in case of Usage Data, collected automatically by the application. Unless specified otherwise all data and permissions requested by the application are mandatory and without it the application is not able to function properly and provide its services. In case the data is specifically stated to be not mandatory to the application than you can opt out from sharing it. Users are responsible for any third-party Personal Data obtained, published or shared through this application and confirm that they have the third party’s consent to provide the Data to the Owner. When you use our AdBlocker Ultimate Browser (“ the browser”) there are some permissions that you agree to and some personal information that we collect. We will describe what permissions you give us, and what we use them for. Permissions to your:

    * Internet – we need this permission in order to access the internet for browsing 
    * External storage – in order to be able to save your downloads, to back up your data and to be able to restore if its needed. 
    * Location – needed for sites that want your location (you can deny locations permissions) 
    * Wake lock – in order to be able to play video 
    * Shortcut – in order to add a shortcut to your home screen 
    * Camera – needed to support WebRTC (you can deny camera permissions) 
    * Audio - needed to support WebRTC (you can deny audio permissions) 
  * ##### The rights of users 

Users may exercise certain rights regarding their Data processed by the application. In particular, Users have the right to do the following: Withdraw their consent previously at any time. Object to processing of their Data if it has been carries out on a legal basis other than consent. Access their Data. Users have the right to learn if Data is being processed by the application. Users have the right to verify the accuracy of their Data and ask for it to be updated or corrected. Users have the right, under certain circumstances, to restrict the processing of their Data. In this case, the application will not process their Data for any purpose other than storing it. Have their Personal Data deleted or otherwise removed. Users have the right, under certain circumstances, to obtain the erasure of their Data from the application. Lodge a complaint. Users have the right to bring a claim before their competent data protection authority. Any requests to exercise User rights can be directed to the company through the contact details provided in this document. These requests can be exercised free of charge and will be addressed by us as early as possible and always within one month.

  * ##### AdBlocker Ultimate for Desktop 

The information collected by the application does not collect any unnecessary data or anything more than needed for the proper functioning of the program. It is kept safely and never sold or in any way disclosed to third parties. We take all necessary measures to protect your information. 

##  Let’s leave all ads behind 

With AdBlocker Ultimate, you will totally forget about all annoying ads. So you can focus on what actually matters – the content you want.
